<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Azert Software</title>
    <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Azert Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Azert Software 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:37:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.azert.co.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AppSec Europe 2017 Comes To Belfast</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/appsec-europe-2017-comes-to-belfast/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2017 21:37:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/appsec-europe-2017-comes-to-belfast/</guid>
      <description>This year my home city Belfast will be hosting AppSec Europe, one of, if not the biggest web security conference in Europe. This is setup by OWasp and the local chapter leaders have been exceptionally busy getting everything organised for this years show, in fact, they were already planning it at last years conference in Rome!
This is a great week long conference featuring three days of instructor lead training (which I highly recommend) as well as two days of talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding SSL to HMail with SSL For Free</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/adding-ssl-to-hmail-with-ssl-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/adding-ssl-to-hmail-with-ssl-for-free/</guid>
      <description>What is SSL For Free? Irun a private mail server on using a t1.micro Windows server on AWS using HMail as the mail server. This serves my @azert.co.uk emails and so far has proved to be extremely reliable, despite the small size of the server. I was running an m3.medium at one stage but it cost a fortune so that didn&amp;rsquo;t last very long!
One of the prerequisites for the mail server I had was SSL support, for obvious reasons of security, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend even more money on certificates.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azert delivers NiMicrolights website</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/azert-delivers-nimicrolights-co-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 21:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/azert-delivers-nimicrolights-co-uk/</guid>
      <description>I have created a new website for local microlight training school NiMicrolights.co.uk.
A full write up of the project can be found over at the project page via the following link . This was a really enjoyable project for me, aircraft and flying being a real passion of mine. I managed this entire project in the evenings over about 5 nights!
It is built using the same tech stack as this blog:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Azert</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/intro-to-azert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 21:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/intro-to-azert/</guid>
      <description>Azert is a new blog by Software Developer Mark Smith who lives in Northern Ireland.
I aim to post how to articles, articles solving problems I&amp;rsquo;ve came across and hopefully other bits of coding information people may find useful.
I will also be using the site to showcase some personal projects I may publish to GitHub. This site is created with the simple aim of spreading knowledge, as well as to help me gleam knowledge from the wider internet.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>