<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Azert Software</title>
    <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Azert Software</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-gb</language>
    <copyright>Azert Software 2017</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:05:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://www.azert.co.uk/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Adding SSL to HMail with SSL For Free</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/adding-ssl-to-hmail-with-ssl-for-free/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2017 13:05:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/adding-ssl-to-hmail-with-ssl-for-free/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;what-is-ssl-for-free&#34;&gt;What is SSL For Free?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I&lt;span style=&#34;letter-spacing: 0.01em;&#34;&gt; run a private mail server on using a t1.micro Windows server on AWS using HMail as the mail server. This serves my @azert.co.uk emails and so far has proved to be extremely reliable, despite the small size of the server. I was running an m3.medium at one stage but it cost a fortune so that didn&amp;rsquo;t last very long!&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the prerequisites for the mail server I had was SSL support, for obvious reasons of security, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to spend even more money on certificates. This is where &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sslforfree.com/&#34;&gt;SSL For Free&lt;/a&gt; comes in. SSL For Free is essentially a web interface over &lt;a href=&#34;https://letsencrypt.org/&#34;&gt;Lets Encrypt&lt;/a&gt; that simplifies creating SSL certificates somewhat. There is a bit of a catch though, while the certificates are free, you do need to renew them, currently this is every 90 days. When you setup an SSL For Free account they will email you in advance of the expiry, so you can take action, there are also programs available that will auto renew for you such as &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Lone-Coder/letsencrypt-win-simple&#34;&gt;LetsEncrypt Win Simple&lt;/a&gt;. Win Simple will also perform all certificate generation etc automatically, so if you can, I would advise using that, unfortunately I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use this as my www.azert.co.uk address points to this site and I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to pollute the site with ACME validation pages (more on this later).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;setting-up-ssl-for-free&#34;&gt;Setting Up SSL For Free&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly navigate to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sslforfree.com/&#34;&gt;SSL For Free&lt;/a&gt; and setup an account, this will then be used to email you for notifications of expiry &amp;amp; you can renew your existing certificates without having to repeat the below steps.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have an account, go to the homepage and enter the domain you wish to setup with SSL.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/29/Setup-Domain.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;validating-you-own-the-domain&#34;&gt;Validating You Own The Domain&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/29/Validation-options.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you click &amp;lsquo;Create Free SSL Certificate&amp;rsquo; you will be taken to the above page. There are 3 options available, each with a description. If you are able to use LetsEncrypt Win Simple then just ignore these steps and use it, it&amp;rsquo;s by far the easiest option. For this guide I used the 3rd option as I couldn&amp;rsquo;t use the manual verification option on my server and had access to the dns through Route 53, provided by Amazon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/29/Manually%20verify.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have verified you own the domain carry on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;copying-to-your-mail-server&#34;&gt;Copying To Your Mail Server&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you have verified you will be taken to a screen with 3 text areas, each representing a different certificate:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private Key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA Bundle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On your Mail Server you will need to create 2 files:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;private.key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;bundle.crt&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can call them anything but this keeps their purpose clear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In private.key copy the Private Key text area contents into the file and save.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the bundle.crt you will need to copy the entire contents of the text areas in order, to create a &lt;a href=&#34;https://support.dnsimple.com/articles/what-is-ssl-certificate-chain/&#34;&gt;certificate chain&lt;/a&gt; without this chain of trust the LetsEcnrypt certificates will not validate. The order they should appear in bundle.crt is:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Private Key&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Certificate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;CA Bundle&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The final step is to setup hMail to use these certificate files.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;hmail-ssl-setup&#34;&gt;hMail SSL Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/29/SSLSetup.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Open hMail admin and go to Advanced -&amp;gt; SSL Certificates and create a new certificate giving it any name you wish. In the Certificate File field then select the bundle.crt file you created earlier. Then in the Private key file field select the private.key file you also created and click &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now you will need to setup the Ports to reference the new Certificate you have created within hMail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/29/PortSetup.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Staying in the Advanced section, open &lt;strong&gt;TCP/IP ports&lt;/strong&gt; and for each select SSL/TLS and choose the certifacte you have created. Click &lt;strong&gt;Save&lt;/strong&gt; for each one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;THe final step is to test it, go to Utilities -&amp;gt; Diagnostics and ensure that connectivity can be achieved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;troubleshooting&#34;&gt;Troubleshooting&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To test your setup and where you may have gone wrong the following are some useful tools:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://mxtoolbox.com/&#34;&gt;MxLookup&lt;/a&gt; - used for testing your domain setup &amp;amp; forwarding etc is correct&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sslshopper.com/ssl-checker.html&#34;&gt;SSLChecker&lt;/a&gt; - to validate your ssl certs&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://slproweb.com/products/Win32OpenSSL.html&#34;&gt;OpenSSL WIndows&lt;/a&gt; - diagnostics tool I found useful when diagnosing why the SSLForFree certificate wasn&amp;rsquo;t validating (it needed the certificate chain)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;renewing&#34;&gt;Renewing&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you get the email advising you to renew, log into &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.sslforfree.com/&#34;&gt;SSL For Free&lt;/a&gt;, you will then be taken to a page showing you existing certificates&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/uploads/2017/01/25/SSL-certs.PNG&#34; alt=&#34;&#34; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Click renew and follow the steps taken earlier to validate your certificate, once re validated you won&amp;rsquo;t need to take any more steps, if you have let it expire, you will need to follow the steps again to create the certificate chain and copy to your mail server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;#Finally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you found this useful or have any further points to add or if I&amp;rsquo;ve missed anything, leave a comment below and I&amp;rsquo;ll get back to you.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Azert delivers NiMicrolights website</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/azert-delivers-nimicrolights-co-uk/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jan 2017 21:45:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/azert-delivers-nimicrolights-co-uk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have created a new website for local microlight training school &lt;a href=&#34;www.nimicrolights.co.uk&#34;&gt;NiMicrolights.co.uk&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A full write up of the project can be found over at the project page via the following &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.azert.co.uk/project/nimicrolights-website/&#34;&gt;link&lt;/a&gt; . This was a really enjoyable project for me, aircraft and flying being a real passion of mine. I managed this entire project in the evenings over about 5 nights!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is built using the same tech stack as this blog:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Forestry.io&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GitHub Pages&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This stack is such a breeze to use I&amp;rsquo;m hoping to use it in many more projects in the future. Do get in touch if there is a web project you&amp;rsquo;d like to discuss!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to Azert</title>
      <link>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/intro-to-azert/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 21:00:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.azert.co.uk/post/intro-to-azert/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Azert is a new blog by Software Developer Mark Smith who lives in Northern Ireland.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I aim to post how to articles, articles solving problems I&amp;rsquo;ve came across and hopefully other bits of coding information people may find useful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will also be using the site to showcase some personal projects I may publish to GitHub. This site is created with the simple aim of spreading knowledge, as well as to help me gleam knowledge from the wider internet. Certainly, if you come across some code, or solution I post and you think there is a better way, use the comment section to let me know. Constructive criticism is always welcome here!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;about-me&#34;&gt;About me&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I work at Intelligent Environments in the Product Team driving our platform forward to make the end user developer experience as seamless, joyful and fast as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this role I touch on many technologies, including:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GoLang&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;C#&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NoSql (Couchbase)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Javascript&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Linux&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;and many others&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect this blog to cover all of the above and more!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am also father to two girls, have been living with my partner for nearly 10 years and have too many hobbies, including the latest which is microlight flying!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;the-blog&#34;&gt;The blog&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I had a previous version of this written using &lt;a href=&#34;https://ghost.io&#34;&gt;Ghost.io&lt;/a&gt; early 2016, but I enjoyed the building of the site more than the thought of blogging so it sat dormat for many months. Around this time, I&amp;rsquo;d came across static sites but I had already the work done so thought I could revist. Well, fast forward to now and I&amp;rsquo;ve since lost half the code in the great hard drive wipe of 2016 and I&amp;rsquo;d not pushed the final code to GitHub (doh!).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With this in mind I decided to revisit the static site idea and came across a few different options before settling on &lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt;. This is an insanely fast, dependency free, static site generator built in GoLang and i&amp;rsquo;ve found it great to use so far so expect a tutorial in the near future!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would not consider this blog finished at this stage, but from an MVP stand point it&amp;rsquo;s good enough, so expect to see some improvements come as time passes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;# Contacting me&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can contact me through &lt;a href=&#34;https://twitter.com/azert-software&#34;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&#34;https://GitHub.com/azert-software&#34;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt; or leave a comment on this site of course.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>